Makishima has been arrested...
The helmet criminals
have been wiped out.
The case is closed.
Is it all over now?
Kagari is missing.
In Division 2, as well, an Enforcer
escaped in the confusion.
Inspector... Do you
think Kagari would run off?
I would like to show
Cut open my skull
槙島は逮捕
Look into my head
ヘルメット犯罪者たちは壊滅
I don't know why I'm so harsh
一件落着…
I could be so brash
これでお仕舞い
I'm going to clash
縢が行方不明だ
'Cause I feel
二係でも執行官が一人　どさくさに紛れて逃亡を
I can always show
my everything to you
監視官…
縢が逃げるかね
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all again
'Cause I feel
I can always show
my everything to you
If this moment was for me
I try to hear
Lend my ear
Voices inside
One link to join it all
So it goes again
本字幕由诸神字幕组制作 更多字幕欢迎访问http://www.kamigami.org
翻译:死树懒  白心上人   校对:西西   时间轴:葛蔓   压制：娜夏
#17 Iron Heart
Can we... say that we won?
私たち…勝ったと言えるんでしょうか？
Detective work is,
by nature, about treating wounds.
デカの仕事は基本的に対症療法だ
Our investigations start after
there are victims.
被害者が出てから捜査が始まる
In that sense, we lose
before we even start.
そういう意味じゃはなから負けている
But at least with this lost
game we were able to end in a draw.
だが負け試合をせめて引き分けで終わらせることはできた
We just have to settle with that.
それだけで良しとするしかない
What was all that talk about
the safety of the Sibyl System?
結局　シビュラシステムの安全神話って何だったんでしょうか…
A safe and perfect
society is just an illusion.
安全完璧な社会なんてただの幻想だ
俺たちが暮らしているのは今でも危険社会なんだ
The society we live in
now is still a dangerous society.
Dangerous?
危険
In this society, people depend on things
that are convenient but also dangerous.
便利だが危険なものに頼った社会のことさ
Our government made us take risks.
俺たちは政府によってリスクを背負わされていた
But the risks were dispersed
and distributed so cleverly
しかしそれが巧妙に分散され分配されていたので
that no one was able to notice it.
誰も気付けなかった
No, they did notice it, but they
just pretended that they hadn't.
いや…気付いても気付かなかったことにした
Everyone might have
been looking the other way.
誰もが目をそらしていたのかもしれない
Precisely because there was danger...
危険がそこに確かに存在するが故に
they had to act as if there wasn't instead,
in order to keep their sanity.
逆に存在しないものとして扱わないと正気が保てなかった
Do you think the citizens of this town,
including me, were that clever?
この街の市民はそこまで器用だったでしょうか
私も含めて…
I don't like to lump people together
when I speak, since everyone is different...
俺は多種多様な人間を一括りにしたような話し方はあんまり好きじゃないんだが
...but I'll generalize broadly here.
ここはあえて大雑把に行こう
I think humans are clever.
人間は器用なものだと思う
自分の責任を回避する努力を　無意識に行うことができる
We can involuntarily try
to avoid our responsibilities.
余計な話だったな
I guess I'm rambling.
Maybe I'm nervous, too.
俺も浮足立っているのかもしれない
How they're going to judge Makishima...
The problem is what happens next.
槙島聖護をどう裁くか
問題はこれからだ
It's a far more difficult and troublesome
task than shooting a Dominator.
こいつはドミネーターをぶっ放すより 遥かに難しくて厄介な仕事だ
But we can't let him get away.
だが　逃がすわけにはいかない
It's an undeniable fact
that he committed crimes.
やつが罪を犯したことは厳然たる事実だ
In any case, we still have
that idiot Kagari to worry about.
しかし残った心配は　縢のバカヤローのことだ
He split off from us and
went down to the basement.
俺たちと別れて　地下へ向かって
Why did the communication end there?
なぜそこで連絡が途絶えた
It's the day after the nightmarish riots.
This is like dealing with
the aftermath of a pandemic.
まるでパンデミックの後始末だな
A psycho-hazard is a mental disease.
サイコハザードは精神の疾病だ
拡散すればこの有り様だ
When it spreads,
this is how things turn out.
A large number of people
needing mental care...
大規模なメンタルケア　パンクした収容施設
housing facilities
overflowing with people...
economic losses due
to crippled city functions...
都市機能の麻痺による経済的損失…
Makishima was a monstrous man.
槙島というのはとんでもない男でしたね
It's too early to talk in the past tense.
過去形にするのはまだ早い
There's still the matter of his sentencing...
やつの量刑をどうするか
The judiciary has been
abolished for a while now.
裁判制度なんてなくなって久しい今
It'll probably be difficult to prosecute
someone based solely on evidence.
証拠だけで立件するってのはちょっと難題だろうな
We're counting on you, Inspector.
頼んだぜ　監視官
You're acting too friendly, Enforcer.
なれなれしいぞ　執行官
Okay, okay.
へいへい
I've been called in by the Chief.
局長からの呼び出しだ
The cases Makishima was
involved in will be investigated
槙島に関する事件の取り調べは厚生大臣が編成した特殊チームで行う
by a special team formed by
the Minister of Welfare.
The MWPSB has lost the
authority to investigate this case.
公安局は捜査権を失った
Excuse me?
はい
This is quite a unique case.
極めて特異なケースだ
Medical staff always has to be
there when questioning him, too.
取り調べには医療スタッフも常時同席せねばならん
情報の機密性も問題になる
There's also the matter of
keeping the information confidential.
槙島聖護は　過去をさかのぼって様々な事件に関与していた疑いが濃厚です
Shogo Makishima was very likely
involved in various crimes in the past.
事実関係を明らかにするためにも　公安局での尋問は必須です
In order for the facts to come to light,
the MWPSB needs to
be able to interrogate him!
Are there any unsolved cases
in those past crimes you mentioned?
その過去の事件とやらに　未解決のものがあるかね
No... but...
いいえ
しかし…
Makishima will be disposed
of as a research sample.
槙島は研究用の検体として処分される
No, he was disposed of.
いや　処分された
Rather than worrying about
an arrested criminal,
逮捕した人間のことよりも
you have a big problem at
Division 1, don't you?
君の一係は大問題を抱えているだろう
An Enforcer escaped...
執行官が一人逃亡　未だ行方不明
...and he's still missing.
We still don't know if he really escaped.
まだ　逃亡と決まったわけでは…
The Sibyl System has already been restored.
シビュラシステムはすでに復旧している
Enforcer Kagari hasn't been
caught by the surveillance network
縢執行官が監視の網に引っ掛からないのは
because he's been steering
clear of it as he moves about.
それを避けて行動しているからだ
このままじゃ　責任問題になるよ
As it stands, you'll be held responsible.
That's... uhm...
それは　その…
Give me a break!
ふざけるな
Give me an acceptable explanation!
納得のいく説明をしろ
執行官が偉そうに何様のつもりだ
What makes you think you can
talk to me like that?! You're an Enforcer!
そんな立場の話をしてる場合か
This is not the time
to discuss our positions!
It's strange that we aren't
even allowed to question him
俺たちが逮捕したのに
取り調べも許されないなんておかしいだろ
when we were the ones
who arrested him, isn't it?!
It wasn't my decision.
If you want to complain...
俺が決めたことじゃない
文句があるなら…
「文句があるなら局長に直接言え」か
"If you want to complain, talk to
the Chief directly." Is that it?!
I'm an Enforcer. There's no
way I can see the Chief, is there?!
執行官の俺が局長に会えるわけないだろ
If I actually march into her office,
it's you who'll be in trouble, Inspector.
実際に乗り込んでいったら困るのはお前だ　監視官
What's going to happen now?
どうなるんですか？　これ
There probably isn't anything we can do.
どうにもならないんじゃないかしら
At any rate, we'll put everything
we have into the search for Kagari.
とにかく　こっちは縢の捜索に全力を投入する
Depending on his actions,
あいつの行動によっては　別の意味で公安局の命取りになりかねない
it could mean the end of
the MWPSB for different reasons.
It's been a while, Shogo.
久しぶりだね　聖護君
It's good to see
you haven't changed a bit.
変わりないようで何よりだ
You are the MWPSB Chief,
Ms. Kasei... was it?
公安局局長　禾生さん…だったかな
I don't think we know each other.
面識はないと思うが…
Well, my appearance has changed
quite a bit in the past three years, so...
まあ　この三年で僕はずいぶんと様変わりしたからね
First, I need to offer you an apology.
早速だが　君に謝らねばならないことがある
About that book I borrowed
from you a while back...
以前君に借りていた本なんだが
I lost it due to the
troubles that I had to go through.
色々と身辺がごたついたせいで　紛失してしまってね
Hm?
It was quite difficult to
find another copy of that book.
同じものを探すのに苦労したよ
I'm surprised.
驚いたな…
Are you Kouzaburou Touma?
君は　藤間幸三郎なのか
This brings back memories.
It's been three years, huh?
懐かしいな あれからもう三年になるか
When I heard that you fell
into the hands of the MWPSB,
僕は　君が公安の手に落ちたと聞いて
I felt that it was terribly unfortunate.
心底残念に思ったものだ
But... that face... plastic surgery...
しかし　その顔は整形…
No, that's not it. Considering that
body structure, you're a different person.
いや　違うな
体格からして別人だ
Your friend Toyohisa Senguji achieved
whole-body cyberization, too, right?
全身のサイボーグ化は　お友達の泉宮寺豊久も実現していたよね
だがここまで完璧な義体化技術は民間には公開されていない
But artificial body
technology that is this flawless
hasn't been made open to the public.
生身の人間とまったく見分けがつかないだろ
You can't tell the difference between
this body and a human body at all, can you?
Nothing of the Kouzaburou Touma
you know is left except his brain.
君の知っている藤間幸三郎は脳だけしか残っていない
What's going on? The culprit
of those grotesque serial killings
どういうことなんだ
あれだけ世間を騒がせた連続猟奇殺人犯が公安局のトップだと
that seriously upset society
is now the head of the MWPSB?
冗談にも程がある
It's not even funny.
In a precise sense, that's not the case.
厳密には違う
I'm not the only Joshu Kasei...
禾生壌宗は僕一人ではないし
僕もまた常に禾生壌宗というわけではない
and I'm not always Joshu Kasei, either.
Our brains are unitized so that
they can be swapped easily.
僕らの脳は簡単に交換できるよう　ユニット化されていてね
We always take turns using this body...
いつも持ち回りでこの体を使っているんだ
Well... it also serves as a bit
of a break from our everyday work.
まあ 日頃の業務の息抜きも兼ねてね
"We" you said?
「僕ら」だと
Yeah, I am only a rep.
ああ　僕はあくまで代表だ
I was only entrusted with talking to
you here since you and I are old friends.
君と旧知の間柄　ということでこの場を任されたにすぎない
We've never shown ourselves to people,
姿を人目にさらしたことはないけれど
but when it comes to our name,
we are famous in a manner of speaking.
僕たち名前だけならそれなりに有名だよ
You should know it, too.
君だって知ってるはずだ
People call us...
世間では僕らのことを「シビュラシステム」と呼んでいる
...the Sibyl System!
How in the hell could they say
that Kagari disappeared from here?!
ここから縢がどう消えるっていうんだ
No matter how worked
up he is, he wouldn't run off.
あいつはどんなにテンパっても逃げたりはしない
どんなときでも自分が生き残る計算ができる男だ
He can calculate how
to survive in any situation.
消えたのはあいつ自身の意思じゃない
He didn't disappear of his own free will.
Then, abduction... kidnapping...
だったら　拉致　誘拐…
Or he was killed in a way that
wouldn't leave any traces of his body.
それとも死体も残らないような殺し方か…
例えばドミネーターのデコンポーザーとかな
For example, using the Decomposer
mode of the Dominator or something.
はい　常守です
Hello, Tsunemori speaking.
A report was received from a citizen.
市民からの通報があった
A broken Dominator was found abandoned.
故障したドミネーターが放棄されていたそうだ
There's at least 20 km between
the Nona Tower and here.
ノナタワーからここまで２０ｋｍはある
Even considering all
the chaos caused by the riots,
いくら暴動の混乱後とはいえ
is it really possible that he wasn't
caught even once by the cameras?
１回もカメラチェックに引っ掛からないなんてことがあるのか
There's no mistake that
this is Kagari's Dominator.
ドミネーターは間違いなく縢のものです
It's damaged quite a bit. Its built-in
GPS isn't functioning, either.
かなりひどく損傷してます
内蔵ＧＰＳも機能していない
Did he break it himself?
So that he can avoid being tracked?
自分で壊した 追跡を逃れるために
Or it was an attempt at deception
あるいはそう思わせたい誰かの偽装工作…
by someone who wants
to make us think that...
As for the incident this time,
今回の事件
目の付けどころはさすがというほかない
your aiming for the right target
was just like you, to say the least.
実際君のお仲間は真実にたどりついていたよ
In fact, your friend
was able to discover the truth.
What the hell is this?!
「何なんだ？こりゃ…」
This is... the true
form of the Sibyl System!
「こいつがシビュラシステムの正体だ」
The Sibyl System is
said to use a PDP model...
シビュラシステムはいわゆるＰＤＰモデル
an extensive network
of supercomputers
大量のスーパーコンピューターによる並列分散処理ということになっている
performing parallel
distributed processing.
It's not really a lie,
but it's far from the truth.
嘘ではないが それは実態とは程遠い
Its ability to utilize a knowledge
base and to perform inferences
ナレッジベースの活用と推論機能の実現は
was not achieved solely by speed
gains in conventional computing.
ただ従来の演算の高速化によって実現したわけではない
By parallelizing the system
that was able to do those things
それが可能だったシステムを並列化し
and expanding it mechanically,
機械的に拡張することで
it was just given massive
processing ability, that's all.
膨大な処理能力を与えただけのことだったのさ
The fact is that a system that expands
and speeds up its ability to think
人体の脳の活動を統合し
思考力を拡張 高速化するシステムは
by incorporating human brain activity
was already put into practical
use more than fifty years ago.
実はもう５０年以上も前から実用化されていた
Precisely because we kept this
technology secret and used it carefully,
この技術を秘匿し 慎重に運用したからこそ
today our country is able to function
as the only country on Earth ruled by law.
わが国は目下のところ地球上で唯一の法治国家として機能できている
We don't even have to destroy this.
「この手でぶち壊すまでもねえ」
If we make this public,
it'll be the end of this country.
「こいつを世間に公表すればこの国はおしまいだ」
And this time...
The system currently
has 247 constituent members.
目下システムの構成員は２４７名
うち２００名ほどが順番にセッションを組むことで
By having about 200 of the 247
connected in sessions at any given time,
we can continuously monitor and judge
この国の全人口のサイコパスを常時監視し
the Psycho-Pass of every
single person in this country.
判定し続けることが可能だ
After all, the ability to judge
using only mechanical programs
結局のところ　機械的なプログラムで判定できるのは
is limited to stress measurements
based on the Hue Check at best.
せいぜいが色相診断によるストレス計測までだ
Specifying Crime Coefficients,
which indicate a more profound human nature,
より深遠な人間の本質を示す犯罪係数の特定には
requires a higher degree
of thinking ability and judgment.
もっと高度な思考力と判断力が要求される
And we are the ones who can make it happen.
それを実現し得るのが われわれなんだよ
What a joke.
お笑いぐさだな
Management of a fair society by machines...
人間のエゴに依存しない 機械による公平な社会の運営
A society that doesn't
depend on human egos...
People accepted the Sibyl System
because that's how it was presented.
そううたわれていたからこそ
民衆はシビュラシステムを受け入れてきたというのに…
And yet, it was actually done arbitrarily
by you, an aggregate of human brains?
その実体が人間の脳の集合体である
君たちによる恣意的なものだったのか
No, it is boundlessly fair.
いいや　限りなく公平だとも
We judge and supervise people.
民衆を審判し監督しているわれわれは
We are already an existence
that transcends mankind.
すでに人類を超越した存在だ
The first qualification to be a constituent
member of the Sibyl System is to have
シビュラシステムの構成員たる第一の資格は
an irregular personality that doesn't fit
in with mankind's conventional standards.
従来の人類の規範に収まらないイレギュラーな人格の持ち主であることだ
Without aimlessly empathizing with others...
いたずらに他者に共感することも 情に流されることもなく
...without being lost to emotion...
...you should be able to oversee human
actions from an outsider's viewpoint.
人間の行動を外側の観点から俯瞰し裁定できる
Such talent is desired.
そういう才能が望まれる
For example, like the way you and I are.
例えば　この僕や君がそうであるように
Oh?
ほう…
I'm a unique human, too,
僕もね　サイコパスから犯罪係数が特定できない特殊な人間だ
whose Crime Coefficient can't be
determined from his Psycho-Pass.
Because of that, I've experienced
a great deal of loneliness.
おかげでずいぶんと孤独な思いをしたものだ
A personality that cannot be measured
even by Sibyl's collective intellect
そのようなシビュラの総意をしても計り知れないパーソナリティーは
is called criminally asymptomatic.
「免罪体質」と呼ばれている
Those with this personality
are distinguished from all citizens
凡百の市民とは一線を画す新たな思想と価値観の持ち主
and have a new ideology
and sense of values.
By finding such valuable
people and taking them in,
そういう貴重な人材を見つけて取り込むことで
the system has continued
to expand its range of thinking
システムは常に思考の幅を拡張し
and gained new possibilities
as an intellectual form.
知性体として新たな可能性を獲得してきた
I see... So after you fell
into the hands of the MWPSB,
そうか…
公安局の手に落ちた君が処刑されることもなく姿を消したのは…
you disappeared
without being executed because...
Yeah, I was added as
a member of the Sibyl System.
ああ　こうしてシビュラシステムの一員に加えられたのさ
初めは戸惑ったがね
I was puzzled at first,
but I was able to understand
its splendor very quickly.
すぐにその素晴らしさが理解できた
他者の脳と認識を共有し
Omnipotence achieved through
the expansion of both understanding
理解力と判断力を拡張されることの全能感
and judgment by sharing
one's cognition with other brains...
I feel like I'm a
prophet right out of a myth.
神話に登場する預言者の気分だよ
I understand everything.
何もかもが分かる
I feel that everything in
the world is under my rule.
世界の全てを自分の支配下に感じる
人一人の肉体が獲得し得る快楽には限度がある
There's a limit to the amount
of pleasure a person can obtain.
But pleasure brought out
by intellect is infinite.
だが知性がもたらす快楽は無限だ
聖護君 君なら理解できるんじゃないか
You can understand that,
can't you, Shogo?
Yeah, it's not really hard to imagine.
そうだな…想像に難くないところではある
僕も君もこの矛盾に満ちた世界で孤立し 迫害されてきた
Both you and I have
been isolated and oppressed
in this world full of contradictions.
But we don't need to grieve over it anymore.
だがもうそれを嘆く必要はない
We should be proud of the nobility of
the mission given to both of us as our fate.
僕たちは共に運命として課された
使命の崇高さを誇るべきなんだ
君もまた しかるべき地位を手に入れるときが来たんだ
The time has also come
for you to take your proper place!
In other words...
つまり…
僕もまたシビュラシステムの一員になれ…と
...you're telling me to become
a member of the Sibyl System?
Your intellect and deep insight...
君の知性 深遠なる洞察力
Those are qualities we eagerly seek out
それはシビュラシステムのさらなる進化のために
われわれが求めてやまないものだ
in order to further evolve the Sibyl System.
It's not to say that we can't
make you a member by force.
強引な手段で君をシステムの一員に取り込むことはできなくはないが…
But..."Value exists only in
the acts based on one's free will"...
「意思に基づいた行動のみが価値を持つ」
というのは君の言葉だったよね
Those were your words, right?
I thought that you'd understand
my explanation and then agree to it.
君ならば僕の説明を理解した上で同意してくれると判断したんだ
機械の部品に成り果てろというのもぞっとしない話だな
The idea of being reduced to a cog
in a machine isn't very appealing to me.
Of course, this would not impede upon
your independence as an individual.
もちろん　これは君の固体としての自立性を損なうような要求ではない
In fact, as you can see,
現に僕はこうして今も藤間幸三郎としての自我を保っている
I'm still maintaining a sense
of my self as Kouzaburou Touma.
All you have to do is say a single word, "yes."
君はただ一言「ＹＥＳ」とうなずいてくれるだけでいい
The operation will be completed
on our way to the Ministry of Welfare
ここにある設備だけで厚生省に向かう道すがら
using the equipment we have here.
外科的な処置は完了する
The Shogo Makishima known to
the public will disappear with your body,
槙島聖護という公の存在は肉体と共に消失するが
君は誰に知られることもなくこの世界を統べる支配者の一員となる
but you'll become one of those who
rule this world with no one being the wiser.
That sounds like the doctor in Balnibarbi.
まるでバルニバービの医者だな
何だって
What?
I'm talking about Gulliver's Travels
by Swift. This is from Part III.
スウィフトの『ガリヴァー旅行記』だよ
その第三編
ガリヴァーが空飛ぶ島ラピュータの後に訪問するのがバルニバービだ
Balnibarbi is the place Gulliver
travels to after the flying island of Laputa.
A doctor in Balnibarbi
comes up with a way to get
バルニバービのある医者が対立した政治家を融和させる方法を思い付く
politicians with conflicting opinions
to reconcile with one another.
２人の脳を半分に切断して
It was a surgery in which
they'd cut each of their brains in half
and then have the two
half brains sewed together.
再びつなぎ合わせるという手術だ
これが成功すると
Once that is done successfully,
they could " produce that moderation
節度のある調和の取れた思考が可能になるという
as well as regularity of thinking."
For the self-conceited lot who think that
この世界を監視し 支配するために生まれてきたとうぬぼれている連中には
"they come into the world only
to watch and govern its motion,"
Swift writes that it is the most
desirable approach.
何よりも望ましい方法だと
スウィフトは書いている
You are a genius at sarcasm, Shogo.
聖護君は皮肉の天才だな
I'm not, but Swift is.
僕ではなくスウィフトがね
You probably thought that I wouldn't
resist until I knew where I was,
場所が分からないうちは抵抗しないと考えたんだろうが
相変わらず君は詰めが甘い
but as usual, you aren't very careful.
You said " on our way to
the Ministry of Welfare" earlier.
さっきの「厚生省に向かう道すがら」という言葉
By saying that,
you hinted that we're in transit.
あれで移動中だとほのめかしてしまった
We're not inside the MWPSB,
so I judged that I could escape.
ここは公安局の中ではない
だから逃げられると僕は判断した
Why?
なぜだ
You should've been able to understand...
君なら理解できたはずだ
...the joy of omnipotence and
the pleasure of governing the world...
この全能の愉悦を…世界を統べる快感を…
Just like God?
さながら神のごとくかね
That might be pleasurable in its own way,
それはそれで良い気分になれるのかもしれないが
あいにく審判やレフェリーは趣味じゃないんだ
but unfortunately I'm not
into being an umpire or a referee,
as I couldn't genuinely
enjoy the game if I were one.
そんな立場では 試合を純粋に楽しめないからね
I love this game that people
call life from the bottom of my heart.
僕はね この人生というゲームを心底愛しているんだよ
So I'd like to continue to participate
in it as a player forever and ever.
だからどこまでも プレーヤーとして参加し続けたい
S-Stop it!
や…やめろ…
Are you afraid of dying even
after gaining the perception of God?
神の意識を手に入れても死ぬのは怖いかい
There's no way that I could love someone
But I want someone to love me
Even if yesterday could
continue unchanging into forever
You and I would never get anywhere
God... where did you go?
I don't hear any response,
but that's how it always is
Are you still here?
You'll never walk alone
I'll go with you
No matter the sin,
I'll bear the burden for you
I'll walk an uncharted path
All alone with you
Sorry for calling you so late.
夜分失礼する
狡噛慎也の番号で間違いなかったかな
Am I correct that this
is Shinya Kogami's number?
Today, I came to know
the true form of the Sibyl System.
今日 シビュラシステムの正体を知ったよ
It's not something worth
putting your life on the line to protect.
あれは君が命懸けで守るほど価値のあるものではない
それだけを伝えておきたくてね
I just wanted to let you know that.
Well then, I'll see you around.
では　いずれまた…
Hey, Gino! What the hell happened?!
おいギノ いったい何があった
お前…どこでそれを…
Where... did you hear about it?
So what happened?!
どうなんだ
まだ確認は取れていないが
It hasn't been confirmed...
槙島を乗せた輸送機が…
...but the transport
aircraft Makishima was on...
...seems to have crashed.
墜落したらしい…
A world where humans' state of mind and the tendency of their
personalities can be quantified. While all sorts of inclinations
are recorded and policed, these measured numbers
used to judge people's souls are commonly called "Psycho-Pass."
This story is fiction.
The names of all individuals and organizations that appear in the show
are fictitious and have no relation to those in existence in the real world.